<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Red Stone Data</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Red Stone Data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>S4 Classes in R with Fire Emblem Heroes Data</title>
      <link>/2018/05/23/s4-classes-in-r-with-fire-emblem-heroes-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/23/s4-classes-in-r-with-fire-emblem-heroes-data/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionFollowing my last few posts, in this entry we’ll again work with Fire Emblem Heroes data but on the subject of Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) in R. R has been described before as being a bit awkward with respect to OOP, with 3 different types of class systems: S3, S4 and RC. In this quick post, we will focus on S4 classes and use them to build a generic character class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Fire Emblem Heroes data</title>
      <link>/2018/04/05/analyzing-fire-emblem-heroes-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/05/analyzing-fire-emblem-heroes-data/</guid>
      <description>Introduction(Edited April 18th, 2018)
This is a continuation of my previous post, in which we scraped data about the mobile game Fire Emblem Heroes using the R package rvest. This time, we’re going to do some exploratory data analysis to get a better idea about the characters in the game and do some clustering analysis on the characters.
Loading librarieslibrary(ggplot2)library(reshape2)library(ggthemes)library(proxy)library(ggdendro)library(WGCNA)library(dynamicTreeCut)library(ggrepel)Data analysisIn my last post, we obtained character stats data, as well as movement and weapon type information:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fire Emblem Heroes data with rvest</title>
      <link>/2018/04/04/fire-emblem-heroes-data-with-rvest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/04/fire-emblem-heroes-data-with-rvest/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionIn this post, we will attempt to collect some data about the mobile game Fire Emblem Heroes by Intelligent Systems and Nintendo. To do this, we’ll use the rvest package to scrape data from the Fire Emblem Heroes Gamepedia page
Loading packageslibrary(&amp;quot;rvest&amp;quot;)Scraping dataFire Emblem Heroes is a tactical RPG game in which players compete against the AI by trying to defeat their teams, composed of up to four characters (heroes).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>